Hayden Cai

I am a self-driven front-end developer and have been in the industry for 2 years. have a keen eye for detail and most of my working life has been dedicated to creating stunning websites for clients. Equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, Restful API etc. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Work History

2022-04 -Current

Software Developer

Exco Parters, Melbourne, VIC

Working with Bendigo and Adelaide Bank

- Stack used includes styled-components, Typescript, Next.js, React(hooks,reducer), GraphQL, Apollo Client, BFF(Backends For Frontend Pattern), TypeGraphQL, Material-UI, Formik,API Gateway
- Designed and implemented a GraphQL API experience layer that integrates Node.js RESTful API microservices.
- Implemented the front end in React.js, TypeScript, and Apollo GraphQL, configured with Webpack, Babel, and Eslint.
- Wrote unit testing for React component by using Jest

2020-08 -Current

Front End Developer

Arkade, Melbourne, VIC

- Stack used includes HTMLS, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Sass, Less, Typescript, Next.js, React(hooks,reducer), GraphQL, Shopify Plus, Prismic (Content Management System), Algolia, Vercel built for Next.js ,Zendesk
- Assisted in building reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Collaborated with designer, product, and back-end teams to make sure the code implementation meet

Contact

Address

Melbourne, VIC, 3168

Phone

041-078-0822

E-mail

ianyaheng822@gmail.com

Skills

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript(ES6), GraphQL, Apollo Client, BFF(Backends For Frontend Pattern), TypeGraphQL, Material-UI, TypeScript, jQuery,Next.js, ReactJS(hooks, reducer), Typegraphql,

Back End: nodejs
Database: mySQL,

MongoDB

Develops Tools & Platforms:

Jira, Github, Gitlab, Postman, Jira

Methodologies: Agile, Figma, Prismic, Shopify Partner, in Vision

Other: Restful API, GraphQL,

Shopify API

design requirements, business specifications.

 Worked as client support to provide effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.

2020-06 - Full Stack Developer(intern)

SettleEasy, Melbourne, VIC

- Stack used includes HTMLS, CSS3, React, StoryBook, MySQL, Nodejs
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for project plans.

2019-04 - Front End Developer(Intern) 2019-05

JR Academy, Melbourne, VIC

- Implemented web application with reactJS,
 JavaScript(ES6), jQuery,HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap
 4, and responsive design.
- Utilized Postman, Trello, InVision and interactive mockup to aid development, testing and documentation generation for project

Education

2020-08

2019-08 - Diploma of Information Technology: Web 2020-01 Development Coding Bootcamp(full-time)

Coder Academy - Melbourne

Recipient of Women Technology Scholarship

 Coursework in JavaScript, React, Node.js, Ruby on Rails

2019-01 - Front End Development

2019-03

JR Academy - Melbourne

Coursework in JavaScript, React, Node.js, C#

2009-08 - Bachelor of Design

2013-08

Southwest Forestry University - China